<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Felix mihi favit</title>
    <link>https://felixmihifavit.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Felix mihi favit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>felixlosada@outlook.com (Felix L)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>felixlosada@outlook.com (Felix L)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://felixmihifavit.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>American Ceasar: How the US census divides and conquers racial individuality and fosters generalisation</title>
      <link>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/english-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>felixlosada@outlook.com (Felix L)</author>
      <guid>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/english-work/</guid>
      <description>Ah, white, hispanic or latino , black or african-american or asian.
The great generalisation of our generation. Some things come easy, and some things come hard. The United States&amp;rsquo; census has been silently dividing racial groups and conquering racially fuelled discussion. The American experiment has brought large and thorough change throughout every area of social culture, federal and governmental change. These beneficial ammendments to the systems that fuel one the richest and most powerful countries on this earth have positively - yet negatively - affected the general masses worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debate Formats</title>
      <link>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/debate-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>felixlosada@outlook.com (Felix L)</author>
      <guid>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/debate-formats/</guid>
      <description>The following was posted on csun.edu on Glen Whitman&amp;rsquo;s debate website.
There are several different formats for debate practiced in high school and college debate leagues. Most of these formats share some general features. Specifically, any debate will have two sides: a proposition side, and an opposition side. The job of the proposition side is to advocate the adoption of the resolution, while the job of the opposition side is to refute the resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Case</title>
      <link>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/how-to-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>felixlosada@outlook.com (Felix L)</author>
      <guid>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/how-to-case/</guid>
      <description>The following was posted on csun.edu on Glen Whitman&amp;rsquo;s debate website.
Think of the process of casing as a funnel. The top of the funnel is wide, because you want to be considering as many cases as possible. But the bottom of the funnel is narrow, because the set of cases that actually make good debates is much smaller.
So the first step in casing is to think of as many cases as you can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Hand Tab a Debate Tournament</title>
      <link>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/hand-tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>felixlosada@outlook.com (Felix L)</author>
      <guid>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/hand-tab/</guid>
      <description>The following was posted on csun.edu on Glen Whitman&amp;rsquo;s debate website.
This page contains a detailed description of my method for hand-tabulating a debate tournament, as a guide for tab directors. I have developed this method over several years of doing tab, so it includes numerous innovations that I&amp;rsquo;ve adopted over that time. My method is certainly not the only way of doing tab, nor do I claim it&amp;rsquo;s the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Run a Damn Good Debate Tournament</title>
      <link>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/debate-tournament/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>felixlosada@outlook.com (Felix L)</author>
      <guid>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/debate-tournament/</guid>
      <description>The following was posted on csun.edu on Glen Whitman&amp;rsquo;s debate website.
This is a guide for debate teams trying to run a parliamentary debate tournament for the first time, as well as for more experienced teams that need a refresher.
In writing this, I&amp;rsquo;m assuming a number of things. First, I assume you want to run a standard, five-round tournament in the usual American Parliamentary Debate Association (APDA) format. Second, I assume my reader is the Tournament Director.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logical Fallacies and the Art of Debate</title>
      <link>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/logical-fallacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>felixlosada@outlook.com (Felix L)</author>
      <guid>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/logical-fallacies/</guid>
      <description>The following was posted on csun.edu on Glen Whitman&amp;rsquo;s debate website.
Introduction This is a guide to using logical fallacies in debate. And when I say &amp;ldquo;using,&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t mean just pointing them out when opposing debaters commit them &amp;ndash; I mean deliberately committing them oneself, or finding ways to transform fallacious arguments into perfectly good ones.
Debate is, fortunately or not, an exercise in persuasion, wit, and rhetoric, not just logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Things Debaters Should Know About Economics</title>
      <link>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/about-econ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>felixlosada@outlook.com (Felix L)</author>
      <guid>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/about-econ/</guid>
      <description>The following was posted on csun.edu on Glen Whitman&amp;rsquo;s debate website.
This is a list of ten things that debaters should know about economics. The purpose of this page is not to provide a full education in economics, but to provide ammunition for debate rounds. I have written the items in broad terms, so that the breadth of their applicability is apparent. As many of the examples indicate, economic ideas can be used in a variety of contexts (legal, political, moral, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twelve Things Debaters Should Know About Law</title>
      <link>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/about-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>felixlosada@outlook.com (Felix L)</author>
      <guid>https://felixmihifavit.com/post/about-law/</guid>
      <description>The following was posted on csun.edu on Glen Whitman&amp;rsquo;s debate website.
This is a list of twelve things (actually, twelve sets of things) that well-informed debaters should know about law and the legal system. If you know the items in the list, you won&amp;rsquo;t be a legal expert, but you&amp;rsquo;ll know enough to survive legal debate rounds. Since I am not a lawyer, I do not claim that my explanations are definitive or comprehensive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
